pharmacompass.com 2019-12-20

# Privacy Policy | PharmaCompass.com

When you use PharmaCompass’ services, you entrust us with personal information (Personal Data). PharmaCompass.com’s Privacy Policy sets out what information we collected, and how we use it. 

1\. Our Commitment to Protect Your Privacy

At PharmaCompass, we provide information to develop relationships and promote industry knowledge for companies engaged in businesses related of pharmaceutical drug discovery, development and manufacturing. 

We are committed to protecting your Personal Data and your privacy. To ensure that you can make informed decisions and feel confident about sharing certain personal information with us, please read this Privacy Policy to understand who we share your Personal Data with and for what purposes, and the choices you have concerning how your Personal Data is collected and used by us. We may also provide further privacy collection notices highlighting certain uses of your Personal Data, together with the ability to opt in or out of certain uses, when we collect Personal Data from you.

The laws of certain countries require us to provide you with additional information about our processing activities and we have included separate appendices to deal with these. As well as this document, please refer to the appendices which apply to you.

We will notify you of any changes to our Privacy Policy, including by posting the revised policy on www.pharmacompass.com. The changes will be effective from the date of posting.

This Privacy Policy applies only to websites controlled by LePro PharmaCompass OPC Pvt. Ltd. namely www.pharmacompass.com. This Privacy Policy does not apply to personal information that is collected offline.

Please note the arbitration provision set forth below, requiring you to arbitrate any claims you may have against PharmaCompass on an individual basis. EXCEPT WHERE AND TO THE EXTENT PROHIBITED BY LAW, ARBITRATION ON AN INDIVIDUAL BASIS MEANS THAT YOU WILL NOT HAVE, AND YOU WAIVE, THE RIGHT FOR A JUDGE OR JURY TO DECIDE YOUR CLAIMS, AND THAT YOU MAY NOT PROCEED IN A CLASS, CONSOLIDATED, OR REPRESENTATIVE CAPACITY.

2\. The Personal Data We Collect

We will collect and process some or all of the following Personal Data about you:

Information about you

PharmaCompass collects (i) personal information voluntarily supplied by you when you register or utilize the services on our website, and (ii) tracking information collected as you navigate the our website. 

We note that over time, non-personal information could become personal information through regulatory developments, technological advancements, or co-mingling with personal information. The types of personal information we collect from you depends on the features you use on our website.

In particular, PharmaCompass collects the following information from and about you:

  * User Information – We may collect personal information from you when you sign up on our website to receive information from PharmaCompass or to contact us to utilize the services available on our website. That personal information may include, among other things, your full name, email address, phone number and other information you provided to us.
  * Demographic Information– We may collect your demographic information, such as your age, gender, city, state and country.
  * Usage Information– We may collect data information about how you and your devices interact with the Site(s). This could include features you use, the web pages you visit and the search terms you enter. This could also include data information about your devices and the network you use to connect to our services, including IP addresses, device identifiers and data information about the performance of the services you use on the website and any problems you experience with them.
  * Location Information– We may collect your location information. This information may help us provide recommendations to you based on your location, serve you with advertisements or direct you to a product or service that we believe may be of interest to you.
  * Content and Other Information You Provide to Us– We may collect additional content and information that you voluntarily provide us, such as when you post an enquiry or comment, submit a complaint or send us feedback.
  * Public data and posts– This may consist of comments or content that you post on the services and the personal information about you that accompanies those posts or content, which may include a name, email address, user name, or comments.
  * Google Analytics– To help facilitate the delivery of relevant content, we use Google Analytics. Google Analytics uses cookies to report on user interactions on our and others’ websites. We use the data collected for optimizing marketing, refining advertising and/or programming strategies and generally making advertising more effective. Google provides a complete privacy policy and instructions on opting-out of Google Analytics here. Note that Google’s opt-out mechanism is specific to Google activities and does not affect the activities of other ad networks or analytics providers that we may use.
  * Clicky Analytics– To further help facilitate the delivery of relevant content, we use Clicky Analytics (a software solution provided by Roxr Software Ltd). Clicky collects information from users and the following information are sent to their servers by default when a user visits our web site. URL & Title of pages viewed, URL & Title of any links that are clicked on pages viewed, Referrer, User agent, Browser language, Screen resolution, x/y coordinates of mouse events, Unique ID tracking cookie ("UID"). The European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) considers this to be Personal Data, even though it is randomly generated and does not identify users or reveals anything else about users. Its sole purpose is to more accurately track unique visitors. IP addresses ("IP"), IPs are anonymized before processing, but PharmaCompass has the option to disable this, in which case they are considered Personal Data. Per Article 6 of the GDPR, processing of UID and IP Personal Data is lawful and does not require a user's direct consent because it is "necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests" of web sites using the service. These legitimate interests include but are not limited to (i) Assembling statistics regarding the use of a web site. (Accurately counting unique visitors is a vital statistic for any web site) (ii) Preventing fraud and abuse, and maintaining information security. (Full IP addresses are necessary for this type of usage). Recital 47 of the GDPR states: "The processing of Personal Data strictly necessary for the purposes of preventing fraud also constitutes a legitimate interest".
  * Audience Based Data – We also receive audience based data (such as pixel traffic and conversion data) from social media platform providers, including Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter and others based on non-identifiable information such as IP addresses. We use this information to serve ads to you and marketing tracking. To block or limit this activity, please visit the sites below: 
    * Twitter: https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405
    * Facebook: You should see a link to the opt-out when you select “Why am I seeing this?” when using Facebook. You can also select “Hide all from this advertiser” within Facebook to stop seeing our ads. More information can be found on Facebook's site here: http://www.facebook.com/business/help/1415256572060999
    * LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/62931/manage-advertising-preferences

3\. How we collect Personal Data

(1) Active Collection

As mentioned above, We will collect some Personal Data from you directly. , at the time you supply information to us via using our website. For instance, if you contact us with a question or request for assistance and/or information, we may store your communications, including any personal information you include in them, so we can effectively respond to you. If you do not want us to collect your personal information, please do not provide it to us.

(2) Passive Collection

We may collect information passively while you are visiting or interacting with our website. We call this “passive” collection because you may not know that this information is being collected. Here are some examples of the information that is collected via website and a description of how this information is used:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) addresses– Your IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send your information, such as the webpages you view. We use this information to deliver our webpages to you upon request, tailor our website to the interests of our users and measure traffic within our website.
  * Cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies– A cookie is a small text file that may be used to collect information about your activity on the website. For example, when someone visits a page within our website, a cookie is placed on the user’s machine (if the user accepts cookies) or is read if the user has visited the website previously. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to allow us to count users who have visited certain pages of our website and to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns. When used in HTML-formatted email messages, web beacons can tell the sender whether and when the email has been opened. Web beacons are embedded invisibly on webpages. For more information, please see Section 9 below.

4\. Why we collect and use your Personal Data

PharmaCompass uses your personal information for a number of purposes including the following:

  * provide you with information support services and to respond to enquiries; 
  * to measure and improve those services and features;
  * for internal record keeping;
  * to invite you to participate in surveys or research about PharmaCompass;
  * to alert you to special offers, updated information from PharmaCompass or other third parties, or to forward promotional materials.
  * to inform you of upcoming events;
  * to send our newsletters;
  * to invite businesses to advertise or benefit from industry events;
  * to use IP addresses to identify the location of users, to block disruptive use, to establish the number of visits from different countries;
  * to analyze and improve the activities and content offered by the PharmaCompass website to provide you with the most user-friendly navigation experience. We may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) for marketing and strategic development purposes.
  * to notify you about a material change to this Privacy Policy , if necessary, or to contact you in response to sign-up forms. 
  * to protect the rights of PharmaCompass and others. There may be instances when we may disclose your personal information, including situations where we have a good faith belief that such processing is necessary in order to: (i) protect, enforce or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety or property of PharmaCompass, our affiliates or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements and terms and conditions); (ii) protect the safety, privacy and security of users of our Site(s) or members of the public; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes;
  * to comply with applicable laws or legal process and/or respond to requests from public and government authorities.
  * for any other legitimate business reasons.

5\. Marketing

PharmaCompass may use Personal Data for to contact you for marketing purposes where you have provided us with consent to do so in accordance with applicable law. Please see below for more information on how to change your communication preferences, including opting out of future marketing communications.

We may communicate marketing and promotions to you by post, telephone, or online (including by email or through your mobile device or via online banner advertisement) and, as appropriate and where required, we will ask you for your consent, or otherwise provide you with the opportunity to choose not to receive marketing, at the time we collect your data. 

Please note that if you choose to unsubscribe or opt out of marketing communication, we will still send you communications if business opportunities are received that PharmaCompass considers can be serviced by your business organization

6\. Who we share your Personal Data with

In certain circumstances, we will disclose your Personal Data to third parties as described below:

  * Service providers, helping to administer the services, products, services educational programs and events. We may share your personal information with companies (including our affiliates) that perform services which we determine can assist in your business services. 
  * Subsidiaries and affiliates to better serve PharmaCompass and its evolving needs;
  * Third parties, who provide products and services of interest to PharmaCompass’ users and customers;
  * Advertising technology companies, such as Google Analytics, Clicky to compile statistics and perform analysis intended to improve our services and serve users with relevant content. You may opt out of advertising by visiting one of these sites: the DAA opt-out site at aboutads.info or the NAI opt-out site at networkadvertising.org/choices;
  * Audience Data Providers, who, in certain countries, we may also work with, such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and others, to receive audience based data (such as pixel traffic and conversion data) from them based on non-identifiable information such as IP addresses; 
  * Competent authorities, including law enforcement, in order to comply with applicable laws or court orders.

7\. Collection and Use of Information from Children

IPharmaCompass is not intended for use by persons under the age 13. PharmaCompass does not knowingly collect information from visitors under the age of 13, and, in the event that we learn that a person under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such personal information.

8\. Your rights and contacting us

8.1 General rights

You have the right (subject to various exceptions and in accordance with data protection legislation in your country) to access certain Personal Data held about you and correct any inaccuracies. We may charge a reasonable fee for the processing of any data access request in accordance with data protection legislation in your country. You also have the right to raise a complaint about our processing with the data protection regulator in your jurisdiction.

8.2 Right to opt out of direct marketing

You have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by indicating that you do not consent to direct marketing at the point at which we collect your Personal Data. You can also exercise the right at any time after we have collected and used your Personal data for direct marketing purposes by following the opt-out instructions contained in the relevant communications.

We will process your unsubscribe as soon as possible, but please be aware that in some circumstances you may receive a few more messages until the unsubscribe is processed.

8.3 Updating information

We will take reasonable steps to try and ensure that your Personal Data is accurate. To help us do this, please notify us of any changes to your Personal Data.

8.4 Contacting us

The Data Protection Officer  
LePro PharmaCompass OPC Pvt. Ltd.  
205 Empire Plaza  
Sultanpur  
New Delhi, INDIA 110030  
dpo@pharmacompass.com   

8.5 For the residents of the EU, you have the right to:

  * Obtain confirmation as to whether or not your personal information exists and to be informed of its content and source, verify its accuracy and request its completion, update or amendment;
  * Request the deletion, anonymization or restriction of the processing of your personal information processed in breach of the applicable law;
  * Object to the processing, in all cases, of your personal information for legitimate reasons;
  * Receive an electronic copy of your personal information, if you would like such a copy for yourself or in order to port your personal information to a different provider;
  * Lodge a complaint with the relevant data protection supervisory authority.

The above rights are subject to applicable limitations and restrictions. In certain cases, your request may be denied based on a legitimate exception such as where we are prevented from disclosing such information based on legal requirements, fraud prevention or security concerns.

Remember that even after you cancel your account or if you ask us to delete your personal information copies of some information from your account may remain viewable in some circumstances where, for examples, you have shared information with other services. Because of the nature of caching technology, your account may not be instantly inaccessible to others. We may also retain backup information related to your account on our servers for some time after cancellation or your request for deletion, to comply with applicable law. 

8.6 Forums, Company Profile Pages and Other Public Posting Areas

Please note that any information you include in a message you post to any company profile pages, forum or other public posting area is available to anyone. If you do not want people to know your email address, for example, do not include it in any message you post publicly or click the appropriate anonymous postings settings.

Please be extremely careful when disclosing any information in forums, company profile pages and other public posting areas. We are not responsible for the use of the information that you disclose in forums, company profile pages and other public posting areas by others (third party).

9\. Use of Cookies on PharmaCompass.com

The website pharmacompass.com use cookies which, among other things, help us to improve your experience of our website and to ensure that it performs as you expect it to.

Cookies are small text files on your device. They are made by your web-browser when you visit a website. Every time you go back to that website, your browser will send the cookie file back to the website’s server. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognize a user’s device. PharmaCompass does not use cookies to match specific user behavior with IP addresses or any other potentially identifiable information. You can find more information about cookies at: www.allaboutcookies.org and www.youronlinechoices.eu

Why does PharmaCompass use cookies?

We use, and allow certain third parties to use, cookies and other similar technologies to operate our Site(s), provide any of our services or other functions and to help collect information. We, or third parties, may use session cookies or persistent cookies. Session cookies only last for the specific duration of your visit and are deleted when you close your browser. Persistent cookies remain on your device’s hard drive until you delete them or they expire. Different cookies are used to perform different functions, which we explain below:

  * Essential. Some cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around PharmaCompass and use their features, such as accessing secure areas of the site. Without these cookies, we cannot enable appropriate content based on the type of device you are using.
  * Browsing and functionality. These cookies allow us to remember choices you make on PharmaCompass, such as your preferred language and the country from which you are visiting, and provide enhanced, more personalized features.
  * Performance and analytics. We use our own cookies and third-party cookies to see how you use PharmaCompass and its services in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to your preferences. In particular, we use: 
    * Google & Clicky Analytics: To help facilitate the delivery of relevant content, we use Google & Clicky Analytics. Google & Clicky Analytics use cookies to report on user interactions on our and others’ websites. We use the information collected for optimizing marketing, refining advertising and/or programming strategies and generally making advertising more effective. Google provides a complete privacy policy and instructions on opting-out of Google Analytics here. Note that Google’s opt-out mechanism is specific to Google activities and does not affect the activities of other ad networks or analytics providers that we may use.
    * Targeted advertising: We receive audience based data (such as pixel traffic and conversion data) from social media platform providers, including AdRoll, Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter and others based on non-identifiable information such as IP addresses. We use this information to serve ads to you and marketing tracking. To block or limit this activity, please visit the sites below:
    * Twitter: https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405.
    * Facebook: You should see a link to the opt-out when you select “Why am I seeing this?” when using Facebook. You can also select “Hide all from this advertiser” within Facebook to stop seeing our ads. More information can be found on Facebook's site here: http://www.facebook.com/business/help/1415256572060999
    * LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/62931/manage-advertising-preferences
  * Third party advertising and social media. There are several ways to manage cookies. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser. If you block certain cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of the personalized features enjoyed by other users of our website. We also note that by blocking or deleting cookies which are “strictly necessary,” you will not be able to access certain features of our website.

In the United States (US), the Network Advertising Initiative also offers a means to opt-out of a number of advertising cookies. Please visit www.networkadvertising.org to learn more. Note that opting-out does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the company or companies from whom you opted-out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your preferences and usage patterns.

10\. Updates on PharmaCompass.com’s Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to PharmaCompass. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use the PharmaCompass website to submit personal information to PharmaCompass. If material changes are made to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by placing a prominent notice on the website. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to keep it up to date on how we are handling your personal information. 

11\. Transmission, storage and security of your Personal Data

11.1 IT Security

No data transmission over the Internet, a website, mobile application or via email or other message service can be guaranteed to be secure from intrusion. However, we maintain commercially reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your Personal Data in accordance with the requirements of data protection legislation.

All Personal Data we collect about you is stored on our or our subcontractors’ secure servers. We comply with our security policies and standards when accessing or using this information and restrict access to your Personal Data to those persons who need to use it for the purpose(s) for which it was collected. You are responsible for keeping any information that we send to you confidential and for complying with any other security procedures that we notify you of. In particular, where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website or mobile applications, we ask you not to share a password with anyone. 

We may post a notice on PharmaCompass if a security breach occurs. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

11.2 Exporting your Personal Data

Your Personal Data may be transferred outside the country in which you are located, including to countries with a lower level of data protection than in the country in which you are located.

11.3 Retention period

We will retain your Personal Data for as long as is necessary for the processing purpose(s) for which it was collected and any other permitted linked purpose (for example where we are required to retain personal data for longer than the purpose for which we originally collected it in order to comply with certain regulatory requirements). Our retention periods are based on business needs and your information that is no longer needed is either irreversibly anonymised (and the anonymised information will be retained) or securely destroyed. 

12\. Dispute Resolution

While using our services, you agree that no other laws other than those of the Republic of India shall apply. If there is any controversy, claim, action, or dispute arising out of or related to your use of our services, or the breach, enforcement, interpretation, or validity of this Privacy Policy or any part of it will be litigated exclusively in the courts of judicature located at New Delhi, India, and you and PharmaCompass consent to personal jurisdiction in those courts.

13\. Links to Other External Sites

PharmaCompass contains links to other sites that are operated by third party companies with different privacy practices. You should remain alert when you leave our site and read the privacy statements of other websites. We have no control over Personal Data that you submit to or receive from these third parties.

The fact that we include links to other websites does not mean that PharmaCompass approves of or endorses any other third party website or the content of that website. We accept no liability for any statements, information, products, or services that are published on or are accessible through any websites owned or operated by third parties.

14\. Contact Us

Your visit to PharmaCompass is subject to this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at the postal and email addresses below

Lepro PharmaCompass OPC Pvt. Ltd.  
205, Empire Plaza   
Sultanpur, New Delhi  
INDIA 110030   
Email: support@pharmacompass.com 

_**This notice is written in English language and may be translated into other languages. In the event of any inconsistency between the English version and the translated version of this notice, the English version shall prevail.**_

_**This Privacy Policy was last updated on 26 May 2018.**_

Copyright © 2019 LePro PharmaCompass OPC Private Limited, All rights reserved.
